Do you find me sadistic?
你以为我在玩性虐待吗?
You know, Kiddo...
知道吗, 小乖...
...I'd like to believe...
...我相信...
...you're aware enough, even now...
...即使现在你还是很清醒...
... to know that there's nothing sadistic...
...知道我不是在和你...
...in my actions.
...玩性虐待的游戏.
At this moment...
此时...
...this is me...
...是我...
...at my most masochistic.
...最痛苦的时刻.
Bill.
比尔.
It's your ba...
这是你的骨肉...
Looked dead, didn't I?
我像是死了,对吧？
Well, I wasn't.
不过我没死.
But it wasn't from lack of trying, I can tell you that.
起码我可以说,我是千辛万苦, 才捡回这条命的.
Actually, Bill's last bullet put me in a coma -
事实上比尔最后一枪, 使我陷入昏迷状态－
a coma I was to lie in for four years.
一场长达四年的昏迷.
When I woke up, I went on what the movie advertisements refer to as
我苏醒之后,就开始了 像电影广告词似的...
"a roaring rampage of revenge."
"怒吼疯狂之复仇".
I roared, and I rampaged,
我怒吼,我疯狂,
and I got bloody satisfaction.
我也得到了血腥的满足.
I've killed a hell of a lot of people to get to this point,
到目前为止,我已经宰了不少人了,
but I've only one more.
但是还剩一个没杀.
The last one.
最后的一个.
The one I'm driving to right now.
就是现在我开车去找的这个人,
The only one left.
唯一剩下的人.
And when I arrive at my destination,
等我到了那里,
I am gonna kill Bill.
我将会..."杀死比尔".
The incident that happened at the Two Pines Wedding Chapel
双松镇结婚教堂发生的案子...
that put this whole gory story into motion
也就是这个故事的起因...
has since become legend.
已经成为一个传奇故事.
"Massacre at Two Pines. "
"双松镇大屠杀",
That's what the newspapers called it.
报纸上是这么称呼它的.
The local TV news called it,
而当地电视台称之为...
"The El Paso, Texas Wedding Chapel Massacre. "
"德州艾帕索市婚礼教堂之惨案"
How it happened, who was there,
怎么发生的,有谁在场...
how many got killed and who killed them -
死了多少人, 是谁杀的...
changes depending on who's telling the story.
众说纷纭,莫衷一是.
In actual fact, the massacre didn't happen during a wedding at all.
事实上,惨案根本不是发生在婚礼上,
It was a wedding rehearsal.
而是婚礼之前的彩排上.
Now, when we come to the part where I say,
彩排到牧师对新郎说...
"You may kiss the bride," you may kiss the bride.
"你现在可以吻新娘" 你现在可以吻新娘.
But don't stick your tongue in her mouth.
不过别把舌头伸进她嘴巴里.
This might be funny to your friends,
你朋友们或许会觉得很有趣,
but it would be embarrassing to your parents.
可是会让你父母难堪.
We'll try to restrain ourselves, Reverend.
我们会控制自己的,牧师.
Y'all got a song?
你们想好要用哪支曲子了吗？
How 'bout "Love Me Tender"? I can play that.
"温柔地爱我"如何？ 这首歌我会.
- Sure. - Yeah.
- 好啊. - 嗯.
"Love Me Tender" would be great.
"温柔地爱我",这曲子很好.
Rufus - he's the man.
如弗斯...就是他.
Rufus, who was that that you used to play for?
如弗斯...你当初是替谁伴奏来着？
Rufus Thomas.
如弗斯・汤玛斯
I was a Drell. I was a Drifter. I was a Coaster.
我曾加入"哲欧","流浪着", 和"游走"乐团.
I was part of the Gang. I was a Barkay.
也曾是"街头小子" 和"巴可"的一份子.
If they come through Texas, I done played with 'em.
只要他们来德州, 我就和他们一起演奏.
Rufus - he's the man.
如弗斯...就是你啦.
- Have I forgotten anything? - Um...
- 我还忘了什么吗? - 我想想...
Oh yes, you forgot, uh, the seating arrangements.
嗯...哦...对了... 你忘了安排坐位了.
- Thank you, Mother. - Yes.
- 谢谢你,老妈. - 嗯.
Now, the way we normally do this -
按照我们的惯例...
we have the bride's side, and then we have the groom's side.
我们有新娘这一边, 还有新郎这一边.
But since the bride ain't got nobody comin',
不过新娘这边没人出席,
and the groom's got far too many people comin'...
而新郎这边又有太多人要来...
Well, yeah, they're comin' all the way from Oklahoma.
对呀,还有人大老远 从奥克拉荷马州来呢！
Right...
对呀...
Well, I don't see no problem with...
那么...我觉得可以...
...the groom's side sharing the bride's side.
...让新郎这边的人, 也去坐到新娘那边.
- Do you, Mother? - I don't have a problem with that.
- 你说呢,老妈? - 我不反对.
But, uh...
但是...
Honey, you know, it would be good if you had somebody come.
亲爱的, 如果你那边 也有人来就更好了.
You know, as a sign of good faith?
这表示...他们也祝福你?
Well, I don't have anybody...
可是, 我真的没有亲朋好友...
...except for Tommy and my friends.
...除了汤米和这些朋友.
- You have no family? - Well, I'm workin' on changing that.
- 连家人都没有吗? - 嗯...很快就会有了.
Mrs. Harmony, we're all the family this little angel's ever gonna need.
哈蒙尼太太,我们就是 这位天使需要的所有的人了.
I'm not feeling very well, and this bitch is starting to piss me off.
我有点不舒服, 肚里的小ㄚ头让我很难受.
So while y'all blather on, I'm gonna go outside and get some air.
你们继续聊,我出去透口气儿.
OK. Um, uh, Reverend, sorry, uh...
好了...牧师...对不起...
- She's gonna go out and get some air. - Yeah. Given her delicate condition...
- 她要出去透透气儿. - 是的,以她现在的身体状况,...
She just needs a few minutes to get it together. She'll be OK.
几分钟就好,她没事儿的.
Right...
哦...
Hello, Kiddo.
哈, 小乖.
- How did you find me? - I'm the man.
- 你是怎么找到我的? - 这还用说.
What are you doin' here?
你在这儿干嘛?
What am I doin'?
我在干嘛?
Well...
哦...
...moment ago I was playin' my flute.
...我刚才在吹箫.
At this moment...
现在...
...I'm lookin' at the most beautiful bride these old eyes have ever seen.
...我这双老眼正看着 我所见过最迷人的新娘.
- Why are you here? - Last look.
- 你为什么会在这儿? - 看你最后一眼.
- Are you gonna be nice? - I've never been nice in my whole life.
- 你会好好的吗? - 我这辈子从来没做过好人.
But I'll do my best to be sweet.
不过我会尽量表现出...和善.
Hmm.
哦.
I always told you...
我总是告诉你...
...your sweet side is you best side.
...你和善的一面是你最好的一面.
I guess that's why you're the only one who's ever seen it.
我想这大概就是为什么 你是唯一见过我和善面的人吧.
- So you got a bun in the oven. - Hmm.
- 瞧...你已经大腹便便了. - 嗯.
- I'm knocked up. - Jeez, Louise.
- 我怀孕了. - 哇.
That young man of yours sure doesn't believe in wasting time, does he?
你的那个小伙子还真不浪费时间啊.
Have you seen Tommy?
你见过汤米没有?
- Big guy in the tux? - Yes.
- 那个穿燕尾礼服的吗? - 对.
Then I saw him.
那我见过了.
I like his hair.
我挺喜欢他的发型.
You promised you'd be nice.
你答应过要好好的喔.
No, I said I'd do my best. That's hardly a promise.
我说过会尽力而为 算不上是承诺吧.
But you're right.
不过你是对的.
What does your young man do for a living?
你未来的夫婿是干哪行的?
He owns a used record store here in El Paso.
他在艾帕索这儿 开了家二手唱片行.
- Ah. Music lover, eh? - He's fond of music.
- 喔...是音乐爱好者,对吧? - 他热爱音乐.
Aren't we all?
我们也是啊?
And what are you doing for a J-O-B these days?
那你最近干什么活儿维生呢?
I work in the record store.
我在唱片行里打工.
Aso.
啊...原来.
It all suddenly seems so clear.
突然间一切都清楚了.
- Do you like it? - Yeah. I like it a lot, smartass.
- 你喜欢那份工作吗? - 嗯,我非常喜欢,你这聪明鬼.
I get to listen to music all day...
我可以成天听音乐...
...talk about music all day. It's really cool.
...聊音乐. 真的酷得很.
It's gonna be a great environment for my little girl to grow up in.
对我的小女儿来说, 这是个合适的成长环境.
As opposed to jetting around the world, killing human beings,
你是拿那种刀头舐血, 杀人掳掠的活儿来比吧？
Precisely.
正是.
Well, my old friend...
那么,老朋友...
...to each his own.
...咱们各走各的路.
However, all cockblockery aside...
不过,先把琐事放一边....
I am looking forward to meeting your young man.
我非常期待见见那小伙子.
I happen to be, more or less, particular whom my gal marries.
我其实很在意我的女人 到底嫁给了谁.
- You want to come to the wedding? - Only if I can sit on the bride's side.
- 你也要来参加婚礼吗? - 除非能安排我坐在新娘这边.
You'll find it a bit lonely on my side.
你会发现我这边有点冷清的.
Your side always was a bit lonely.
你身边一向很冷清.
But I wouldn't sit anywhere else.
但我不会坐其它地方.
You know...
你知道...
...I had the loveliest dream about you...
...我昨晚有个美梦,梦到了你...
Oh, here's Tommy! Call me Arlene.
哦, 汤米过来了! 记得叫我爱琳.
- You must be Tommy! - Uh-huh.
- 你一定是汤米! - 嗯.
Arlene's told me so much about you.
爱琳跟我说了很多关于你的事.
- Honey, you OK? - Oh, I'm fine.
- 宝贝,你没事吧? - 哦,我很好.
Tommy, I'd like you to meet my father.
汤米,让我来介绍我父亲.
Oh, my God!
哇,老天!
Oh, my God, this is great!
哇,老天! 真是太好了!
I'm so glad to meet you, sir... uh, Dad.
我真高兴认识你,先生. 哦...不对...爸爸.
The name's Bill.
我叫比尔.
Well, it's great to meet you... Bill.
哦,真高兴能认识你,比尔.
- Arlene told me you couldn't make it. - Surprise.
- 爱琳跟我说你不能来.. - 给你个惊喜.
That's my pop for ya. Always full of surprises.
我老爸就是这样, 总是出人意料.
Well, in the surprise department...
没错啦,说到"出人意料"...
...the apple doesn't fall far from the tree.
...真是有其父必有其女.
- When did you get in? - Just now.
- 你什么时候到的? - 刚到.
- Did you come straight from Australia? - Of course.
- 直接从澳大利亚来? - 当然.
Daddy, I told Tommy that you were in Perth mining for silver, and...
爸,我告诉汤米,你在澳洲挖银矿,
...no one could reach you.
...没人找得到你.
Lucky for us all, that's not the case.
很幸运的是,这次不一样啦.
So...
我说...
What's this all about? I've heard of wedding rehearsals,
你们这是干嘛呢? 我只听过平装彩排,
but I don't believe I've ever heard of a wedding dress rehearsal before.
但不曾听说盛装彩排.
We thought,
我们想说,
"Why pay so much money for a dress you're only gonna wear once?"
婚纱礼服这么贵, 只穿一次太可惜了.
Especially when Arlene looks so goddamn beautiful in it.
特别是爱琳穿上它 是如此的美丽.
So, I think we're gonna try to get all the mileage we can out of it.
所以我们打算物尽其用.
Isn't it supposed to be bad luck for the groom to see the bride
不是说...新郎在婚礼前 看到新娘穿礼服是不好的预兆.
Well, I guess I just believe in living dangerously.
我是想,活着就该经历些风浪吧.
I know just what you mean.
我恰巧懂你的意思.
Son. Some of us have places to be.
孩子. 有些人还有事呢.
Sure do.
就是说嘛.
Look, we got to go through this one more time. So, why don't you have a s...
我们还得再排练一次, 还是请你去坐...
Oh, my God. What am I thinking? You should give her away!
哦,天哪,我是怎么啦？ 你应该牵着新娘进场才对.
Tommy, that's not exactly Daddy's cup of tea.
汤米,爹地不太喜欢这样.
I think Father would be much more comfortable
我想他还是...
- sitting with the rest of the guests. - Hmm. Really?
- 和其他来宾坐一起会比较自在. - 哦. 真的吗?
That's asking a lot.
要求是过分了.
Oh. OK. Well, forget it.
哦,好吧,那就算了.
But how about we go out to dinner tonight to celebrate?
那今晚吃个饭庆祝一下如何？
Only on the condition that I pay for everything.
我请客才行.
Deal. We got to do this now.
说定了. 我们得彩排了.
- Can I watch? - Absolutely. Have a seat.
- 我能观礼吗? - 当然,请坐吧.
- Which is the bride's side? - Right over here.
- 新娘席在哪边? - 就在这儿.
Mother, here we go!
新郎的妈,开始吧!
Now son, about them vows...
现在,孩子,关于誓言的部分...
Bill...
比尔...
- I just want... - You don't owe me a damn thing.
- 我只想... - 你不欠我什么.
If he's the man you want...
如果他就是你要的男人...
...then go stand by him.
...那就去他身边吧.
- Do I look pretty? - Oh, yes.
- 我漂亮吗? - 哦,当然.
Thank you.
谢谢.
What the hell?
搞什么鬼呀?
No! Bill!
不要! 比尔!
You tellin' me she cut her way through 88 bodyguards before she got to O-Ren?
你是说她杀了88个保镳 才杀到尾连面前?
Nah, there wasn't really 88 of 'em.
不是刚好88人啦.
They just called themselves "The Crazy 88"
他们只是自称"疯狂88人帮".
- How come? - I don't know.
- 为什么? - 我怎知.
I guess they thought it sounded cool.
也许他们觉得这名号很酷吧.
Anyhow, they all fell under her Hanzo sword.
那他们是怎么死在她的半藏刀下?
- She got a Hanzo sword? - He made one for her.
- 她有把半藏刀? - 他铸了一把给她.
Didn't he swear a blood oath to never make another sword?
他不是发过毒誓不再铸刀了吗？
It would appear he has broken it.
似乎他破了誓.
Them Japs sure know how to hold a grudge, don't they?
日本鬼子不是很记仇的吗？
Or maybe...
还是...
...you just tend to bring that out in people.
...你会让人想起旧仇.
I know this is a ridiculous question before I ask it,
恕我冒昧的问个蠢问题...
but you haven't, by any chance, kept up with your... swordplay?
你刀上的功夫还没落下吧？
I, um...
我, 呃...
I pawned that years ago.
几年前我就把刀当掉了.
You hocked a Hattori Hanzo sword?
你把服部半藏的刀当了!?
Yep.
嗯.
It was priceless.
是无价之宝啊!
Well, not in El Paso, it ain't.
在艾帕索算不上什么宝啦.
In El Paso, I got me $250 for it.
我在艾帕索当了250块钱.
I'm a bouncer in a titty bar, Bill.
我在上空舞厅当保镳,比尔.
If she wants to fight with me, all she's got to do is come down to the club
如果她想动手,只要去那儿, 随便找个茬,咱们就能打起来了.
I know we haven't spoken in some time,
我知道我们很久没聊聊了.
and the last time we spoke wasn't the most pleasant,
最后一次聊天也闹的不愉快.
but you've got to get over being mad at me,
但是你不能再生我的气了.
and start becoming afraid of (bleep),
得开始担心她了.
because she is coming, and she's coming to kill you.
因为她要来找你,她来是要你的命.
And unless you accept my assistance, I have no doubt she will succeed.
没有我的帮助,她一定成功.
I don't dodge guilt, and I don't Jew out of paying my comeuppance.
我不会逃避我的罪过, 也不会逃避我应得的报应.
Can't we just... forget the past?
我们难道不能忘掉往事？
That woman...
那个女人...
...deserves her revenge.
...是应该报仇.
And...
同时...
...we deserve to die.
...我们也的确该死.
But then again...
但是, 换句话说...
...so does she.
...她也该死.
So I guess...
所以我说...
...we'll just see.
...咱们走着瞧吧.
Won't we?
行吗?
Late again.
又迟到了.
Budd, can't you tell time?
巴德,你没时间观念吗?
There ain't nobody in here, man.
老兄,还没人上门呢.
- Is that Budd? - Yeah.
- 是巴德? - 对.
Tell him to get his fucking ass back here!
叫他给我滚过来.
OK.
好.
Budd, Larry'd like a word with ya.
巴德,赖瑞有话跟你说.
Take a hit. Be somebody, baby.
吸一口,你就浑然忘我了,宝贝.
You looking for me?
你找我?
I don't know what car wash you worked before you came here
我不知道你以前 在哪家洗车厂打工,
that let you stroll in 20 minutes late, but it wasn't owned by me
迟到20分钟还让你大摇大摆的进来. 不过肯定不是我的.
- and I own a fuckin' car wash. - Do you want me to leave?
- 不过我真他妈的有间家洗车厂. - 要我回避吗?
No, I don't want you to leave. I want you to sit and wait.
不,别走,我要你坐着等.
Larry...
瑞赖...
...there ain't nobody out there, so...
...外面没有客人, 所以...
"There's nobody out there, Larry."
"外面没有客人,赖瑞."
What's your point?
你想说啥?
- That you're not needed here? - My point is...
- 这儿用不着你了? - 我是说...
...I'm the bouncer, and there ain't nobody out there to bounce.
...我是说...我是个保镳, 而现在外面又没人闹事啊.
You saying that the reason...
你是说...
...that you're not doing the job that I'm...
...你没干我付钱给你干的活儿, 是因为没活可干?
- No... - Is that what you're saying?
- 不是... - 你是这个意思吗?
What are you trying to convince me of, exactly?
你到底想要我相信什么?
That you're as useless as an asshole right here?
相信你像这里的屁眼一样 是个没用的废物吗？
Well, guess what, buddy?
猜猜我怎么想,老兄?
I think... you just fucking convinced me.
他妈的,我还真的被你说服了.
Let's go to the calendar.
咱们看看日历吧.
It's calendar time.
看日历咯.
Calendar time for Buddy.
看巴德的值班表喔.
- OK. You working tomorrow? - Yeah.
- 好. 你明天有班吗? - 有.
Mm. No, you're n... You don't even know what fucking day you work.
没有,你明天没班, 你根本不知道哪天有班.
Here. You're not working tomorrow.
看这儿,明天你没班,
You're working Wednesday. Here you are. There you go.
周三才有. 这儿, 看到了吧.
- Workin' Thursday? - Yeah.
- 周四有班吗? - 有.
I don't think so. Friday.
我说没有. 星期五.
I d... There's your name.
我说...这有你的名字.
- If you say so. - There used to be your name. OK?
- 你说了算. - 这里以前有你的名字,懂吗?
- Saturday. There used to be your name. - Oh.
- 星期六. 以前有你的名字. - 哦.
Uh, Monday...
呃, 星期一...
Here. How about that?
瞧. 这样如何?
Fuckin' with your cash is the only thing you kids seem to understand. OK?
现在的年轻人只认得钱, 其他什么都不懂.
Now, I want you to go home till I call you.
你现在回家等我打电话给你,
Till I call you.
等我打给你.
Before you leave, talk to Rocket. She's got a job for you to do.
走之前去找洛姬, 她有事情给你做.
And...
还有...
...the hat.
...那个帽子.
That fuckin' hat.
那个蠢帽子.
That fucking...
那蠢...
How many times have I told you,
我跟你说过多少次,
don't wear that fucking hat here? How many?
不准你在这里戴那个蠢帽子.
Customers wear hats.
客人也有戴帽子呀.
Well, I'm not the boss of the customers.
我不是客人的老板,
I'm the boss of you. And I'm telling you...
我是你的老板. 所以我告诉你...
...that I want you to keep that shit-kicker hat at home.
...我要你把那顶 又蠢又驴的帽子留在家里.
Yeah. Budd, honey, uh, the toilet is at it again.
嗨,巴德,亲爱的, 马桶又坏了.
There's shitty water all over the floor.
粪水流满地..
OK... Rocket.
知道了,洛姬.
- I'll clean it up. - Mm-hmm.
- 我会打扫干净的. - 嗯.
@ How many times
# 曾经多少次 #
@ Have you heard someone say,
# 你听人说过 #
@ "If I had his money,
# 如果我像他一样富有 #
@ I could do things my way"
# 就能做我想做的事 #
@ But little they know
# 但他们却不知 #
@ That it's so hard to find
# 很难找出 #
@ One rich man in ten
# 十个富人中 #
@ With a satisfied mind
# 有一个知足的人 #
@ Once I was wading
# 我也曾拥有 #
@ In fortune and fame
# 财富与名望 #
@ Everything that I dreamed for
# 所有我梦想的一切 #
@ To get a start in life's game
# 人生所需我都曾拥有 #
@ Then suddenly it happened
# 突然之间 #
@ I lost every dime, but I'm richer...
# 我变得一文不名 # # 但是我现在却更富有... #
@ How many times
# 曾经多少次 #
@ Have you heard someone say...
# 你听人说过 #
Now...
现在...
...that gentled you down some, didn't it?
...你可冷静下来了吧?
Yep.
对.
Ain't nobody a badass with a double dose of rock salt dug deep in her tits.
还没哪个坏蛋的奶子上 有双份的岩盐散弹.
Not havin'... tits...
哪个坏蛋也没... 像你的奶子一样...
...as fine...
...漂亮...
...or as big as yours,
...而且和你的一样大.
I can't even imagine how bad that shit must sting.
我难以想像那打在身上有多疼.
Yet...
然而...
...I don't want to, neither.
...我也不想知道.
I win.
我赢了.
Bill.
比尔.
Wrong brother, ya hateful bitch.
猜成我哥哥了,臭婊子.
- Budd. - Bingo.
- 巴德? - 答对啦.
And to what do I owe this dubious pleasure?
是啥事让我有幸接到你的电话？
I just caught me the cowgirl ain't never been caught.
我刚逮到了那个 从没被逮过的女牛仔.
- Did you kill her? - Well, not yet, I ain't.
- 你宰了她吗? - 没,我还没.
I shot her full of rock salt.
我着实给了她一枪岩盐弹.
She's so gentle right now, I could perform her coup de grace with a rock.
她现在乖的不得了, 我随时可以拿个石头了结她.
Anywho...
废话少说...
Guess what I'm holdin' in my hand right now?
猜猜...我现在手里拿什么？
What?
什么?
A brand spankin' new Hattori Hanzo sword.
一把全新的服部半藏刀.
And I'm here to tell ya, Elle,
跟你说,艾儿,
-...that's what I call sharp. - How much?
- 这才叫"锋利"呢! - 多少钱?
Oh, that's hard to say, bein' that it's... priceless and all.
很难说...这是个...无价之宝.
What's the terms?
开价吧?
You get your bony ass down here first thing in the morning...
明天一早你这瘦皮猴...
...with a million dollars in folding cash...
...送一百万捆好的现金过来...
...and I'll give you the greatest sword ever made by a man.
...我就给你这把 人所能造出最好的刀.
Now, how do you like the sound of that?
你觉得如何呀?
Sounds like we got a deal.
听起来咱们像是成交了.
- One condition. - What?
- 一个条件. - 什么?
She must suffer to her last breath.
让她受尽苦头, 直到咽下最后一口气.
Well...
这么嘛...
That, Elle darlin'...
亲爱的艾儿...
...I can pretty much damn well guarantee.
...我几乎敢打包票.
Then I'll see you in the mornin', millionaire.
那么明早见啦...百万富翁.
All right.
好的.
Wakey, wakey.
醒醒咯, 醒醒咯.
Eggs and bakey.
早餐的蛋与腌肉.
I'm done!
完工了!
Get me outta this hole!
拉我出坑!
Good.
好的很.
Whoa, look at those eyes.
哇, 看看那双眼.
This bitch is furious.
这婊子一定气疯了
What did I tell ya?
我说的没错吧.
Is she the cutest little blond pussy you ever saw?
她是不是你 见过最性感的金发尤物?
Or... is she the cutest little
还是...她就是你
I seen better.
我见过更棒的.
You got anything to say?
你有遗言吗?
White women call this "the silent treatment."
白人女子称之为"无言的抗议".
And we let 'em think we don't like it.
咱们得让她们相信, 咱们可不喜欢这样.
You grab the feet, I'll get the head.
你抬脚,我抬头.
Wiggle worm, you see this?
小蠕虫,看到这个吗？
You see it, don't ya?
看到了,对吧？
That's a can of Mace.
那是一罐催泪瓦斯.
You're goin' underneath the ground tonight.
今晚你马上就要入土了.
And... that's all there is to it.
就这么简单.
I wanna bury ya.
我想把你埋了...
I was gonna bury ya...
我想把你...
...with this.
...和这个一起埋了.
But if you're gonna act like a horse's ass...
但是如果你不安份点儿,
...I'm gonna spray this whole goddamn can right in your eyeballs!
我就把他妈的一整罐 直喷到你眼珠子上.
I'll burn 'em right outta your fuckin' head.
会把你眼珠子都给烧出来.
Then you're gonna be blind...
然后你就瞎了...
...and burnin'...
...烧了你'...
...and buried alive.
...再活埋.
Now, what's it gonna be, sister?
你自己选,妹子.
That's a wise decision.
算你聪明.
This is for breakin' my brother's heart.
这一定会伤透了我老哥哥的心.
Once upon a time...
从前...
...in China...
...在中国...
...some believe around the year...
...据说大约在...
...one double aught-three,
...公元1003年,
head priest of the White Lotus Clan, Pai Mei, was walking down a road...
白莲教掌门白眉道长走在街上,
...contemplating whatever it is
思索着只有白眉这种绝世高手 才会思索的问题,
which is another way of saying, "Who knows?" -
换句话说就是, 天晓得他在想什么.
when a Shaolin monk appeared on the road,
有个少林和尚迎面走来,
traveling in the opposite direction.
向他迎面走来.
As the monk and the priest crossed paths...
就在他们擦肩而过时...
...Pai Mei...
...白眉...
...in a practically unfathomable display of generosity,
白眉几乎是高深莫测的 向他友善的点了点头.
The nod...
这点头礼...
...was not returned.
...却没得到回应.
Now, was it the intention of the Shaolin monk to insult Pai Mei?
到底是和尚是有意羞辱白眉,
Or did he just fail to see the generous social gesture?
还是他没注意到对方的社交礼仪,
The motives of the monk remain unknown.
和尚真正的意思无从得知.
What is known...
唯一知道的是...
...were the consequences.
...后果.
The next morning, Pai Mei appeared at the Shaolin temple...
第二天早上白眉来到了少林寺.
...and demanded of the temple's head abbot
...要求掌门方丈...
that he offer Pai Mei his neck to repay the insult.
自刎谢罪.
The abbot, at first, tried to console Pai Mei.
起先方丈想和安抚他,
Only to find Pai Mei was...
却发现白眉...
...inconsolable.
...难消怒气.
So began...
接下来...
...the Massacre of the Shaolin Temple, and all sixty of the monks inside,
...白莲教就血洗少林, 全寺60僧众无一幸免.
And... so began the legend...
然后...传说从此开始...
...of Pai Mei's Five-Point-Palm Exploding-Heart Technique.
...白眉的五指穿心掌.
And what, pray tell, is the Five-Point-Palm
- 五指穿心掌到底是啥? - 非常简单...
the deadliest blow in all of martial arts.
武学中最致命的一招.
He hits you with his fingertips...
他以五指击你...
...at five different pressure points on your body...
...五指不等的内力击在你身上...
...and then lets you walk away.
...然后让你自己逃走.
But once you've taken five steps...
但是你在五步之内...
...your heart explodes inside your body...
...穿心...
...and you fall to the floor, dead.
...倒地而死.
- Did he teach you that? - No.
- 他把这招传给你了吗 - 没有.
He teaches no one the Five-Point-Palm Exploding-Heart Technique.
他的五指穿心掌从不传人.
Now...
说到这儿...
...one of the things I've always liked about you...
...我最喜欢你的一点就是...
...Kiddo...
...小乖...
...is you appear wise beyond your years.
...你看起来比实际的年龄更聪明.
So, allow me to impart a word to the wise:
让我给你这聪明人一点忠告:
Whatever...
无论如何...
...whatever Pai Mei says, obey.
...不管白眉说什么, 你都得服从.
If you flash him, even for an instant, a defiant eye, he'll pluck it out.
即使你短暂地露出些许不敬的眼神, 他立刻把你眼珠子挖出来.
And if you throw any American sass his way...
如果你的美式骄傲触怒了他...
...he'll snap your back and your neck like they were twigs.
...他会把你脊椎 和脖子像小树枝一般地劈断.
And that will be the story of you.
那你就成为一个故事了.
He'll accept you as his student.
他答应收你为徒了.
- What happened to you? - Nothin'.
- 你怎么啦? - 没事儿.
- Get in a fight? - Friendly contest.
- 和他动手了? - 朋友间过个招罢了.
Why did he accept me?
他怎么会答应收我的?
Because he's a very, very, very old man.
因为他已经很老很老了.
And like all rotten bastards...
和其他老不死的王八蛋一样...
...when they become old, they get lonely.
...他愈老就愈寂寞..
Which has no effect on their dispositions,
年纪改不了他的脾气,
but it does teach them the value of company.
但也让他学到了,有个伴儿的重要.
Whew. Oh.
哇赛.
Just seein' those steps again makes me ache.
光是瞧这些台阶,我腿就软了.
You're gonna have a lot of fun
以后你挑着水桶上上下下的, 可有你乐的啦.
When will I see you again?
我何时能再见到你?
That's the title of my favorite soul song of the seventies.
就像我最喜欢的70年代, 一首黑人灵歌的歌名.
- What? - Nothin'.
- 啥? - 没什么.
When he tells me you're done.
等他说你可以出师时.
When do you think that might be?
你想会是何时?
That, my dearest, depends entirely on you.
亲爱的,那全看你自己了.
Now remember, no sarcasm, no backtalk.
记住,切勿讥讽,切勿顶撞.
At least not for the first year or so.
起码头一两年里.
You're gonna have to let him warm up to you.
你得给他时间来 慢慢让你进入状况.
He hates Caucasians, despises Americans,
他讨厌白人,藐视美国人,
and has nothing but contempt for women.
更不喜欢女人.
So in your case... it might take a little while.
所以像你这种情行, 得多花点儿时间了.
- Adios.
再见啦
Master...
师父...
Your Mandarin is lousy.
你的汉语好差. 我一个字也听不懂.
You are not to speak unless spoken to.
我没要你说话,你就别说.
Is it too much to hope -- you understand Cantonese?
你的汉语好呢, 还是你的广东话好？
I speak Japanese very well--
我的日语很好...
I didn't ask if you speak Japanese --
我没问你日本话, 也没问你蒙古话.
I asked if you understand Cantonese?
我问你会不会说广东话？
A little.
一点点.
You are here to learn the mysteries of Kung Fu, not linguistics.
你是来学武的,不是学讲话.
If you can't understand me --
如果你不懂汉语,
I will communicate with you like I would a dog.
就像狗一样.
When I yell, when I point, when I beat you with my stick!
我会斥喝你,命令你,用棍打你！
Bill is your master, is he not?
你的师父是不是比尔？
Yes, he is.
是的.
Your master tells me -- you're not entirely unschooled.
你师傅说过你曾经学过武术.
What training do you possess?
你学过些什么？
I am proficient in Tiger-Crane Style,
我精通虎鹤拳.
and I am more than proficient in the exquisite art of the Samurai sword.
更精通日本武士道剑术.
The exquisite art of the Samurai sword. Don't make me laugh!
哼～日本剑道, 开什么玩笑！
Your so-called exquisite art, is only fit for --
你所谓的剑道不值个屁 你就更加笨.
Japanese fat heads!
你居然敢正视我
Your anger amuses me. Do you believe you are my match?
看你的脾气都可以学武, 你觉得本道的功夫跟你比如何？
No.
不知.
Are you aware I kill at will?
你知道本道会杀人吗？
Yes.
知道.
Is it your wish to die?
那么你是想死？
No.
不.
Then you must be stupid...
傻瓜.
Rise, and let me look at your ridiculous face.
本道好想看看你有多傻.
Rise.
起身.
So my pathetic friend... Is there anything that you can do well?
亏你还学过虎鹤拳, 刚才走了一百来台阶就在喘了.
What's the matter?
我看你不单是傻.
Cat got your tongue?
身体也很虚啊.
-- Oh yes, you speak Japanese.
喔,对了,你会说日本话.
I despise the Goddamn Japs!
我最恨日本人！
Go to that rack.
去兵器架那边.
Remove the sword.
拔那把剑.
Let's see how good you really are.
我要看下你的武功有多深.
If...
出招..
...you land a single blow,
如果我输给你的话
I'll bow down and call you master.
我干脆拜你为师.
From here you can get an excellent view of my foot.
你看到我的功夫了吧, 试我的脚法.
Your swordsmanship -- is amateur at best.
你的剑术...只是一般入门的水平.
Your so-called kung-fu -- is really -- quite pathetic.
残废也比你强.
I asked you to demonstrate -- what you know -- and you did...
我已经给你机会显示一下你的武功, 我看到了.
Not a goddamn thing!
你一点都不会.
Let's see your Tiger Crane -- match my Eagle's Claw.
现在我要你以虎鹤拳 和我的鹰爪拳比试一下.
Like all Yankee women...
你和其他美国女人一样.
...all you can do is order in restaurants and spend a man's money.
只知道在餐馆点菜,花男人的钱.
Excruciating -- isn't it?
痛吗？ 我问你呢？
Yes!
痛!
If it was my wish...
你相不相信我...
...I could chop your arm off.
...随时能砍下你的手臂.
No, please don't!
不要!
It's my arm now. I can do what I please.
你相不相信我想怎样就怎样.
If you can stop me -- I suggest you try.
如果你不想我砍你的手...动手！
I can't.
我不行.
Because you're helpless?
打不过吧.
Yes.
对.
Have you ever felt this before?
你以前试过这种滋味吗？
No.
没有.
Compared to me -- you're as helpless as a worm fighting an eagle?
你的功夫和我比,简直是班门弄斧.
YES!!!
是的!!!
THAT'S THE BEGlNNlNG!
现在开始.
Is it your wish to possess this kind of power?
你想不想学 我刚才和你打的这套拳？
Yes!
想!
Your training will begin -- tomorrow.
从明天开始你要练武
Since your arm now belongs to me...
你的手臂属于我...
...I want it strong.
...我会将它练得结实.
Can you do that?
你能不能做到像我这样?
I can, but not that close.
可以,不过还差你一节.
Then you can't do it.
那就是不行了！
What if your enemy -- is three inches in front of you...
如果敌人离你的身体只有三寸...
...What do you do then...
...你怎么对付他?
...Curl into a ball...
抱头鼠窜...
...or do you put your FlST through him?
...还是用拳打穿他?
Now begin.
现在开始.
It's the wood that should fear your hand --
练拳头不应该是你怕木头,
-- not the other way around.
应该是木头怕你.
No wonder you can't do it -- you acquiesce to defeat --
你之所以打不穿木头,
-- before you even begin.
是因为你用手之前已经认输了.
If you want to eat like a dog...
如果你像狗一样吃东西.
You can live and sleep outside like a dog.
我就让你像狗一样住外面.
If you want to live and sleep like a human...
如果你想像人一样的话,
...pick up those sticks.
把筷子拿起来.
Come on, you bitch.
快, 你混蛋.
OK, Pai Mei.
好, 白眉.
Here I come.
我来了.
May I have a glass of water, please?
请给我一杯水?
-Sothat's a Texas funeral? - Yep.
- 原来那就是德州式葬礼? - 对.
I have to give it to ya, Budd.
我不得不承认你还真行,巴德.
That's a pretty fucked up way to die.
这种死法还真凄惨.
What's the name on the grave she's buried under?
她墓碑上是什么名字？
Paula...
宝...
...Schultz.
休兹.
Can I look at the sword?
能看看那把刀吗?
That's my money right there in that red bag, isn't it?
我的钱就在那红箱子里,对吧?
It sure is.
没错.
Well then, it's your sword now.
那好,刀是你的啦.
(blender whirring)
那么,这就是那把半藏的刀咯!
What's that you said?
你刚说啥？
So this is a Hattori Hanzo sword?
这就是服部半藏铸的刀?
That's a Hanzo sword, all right.
没错,就是半藏的刀.
Bill tells me you once had one of these of your own.
比尔告诉我, 你曾经也有一把他的刀.
Yeah, once.
对, 曾经.
Yeah? How does this one compare to that?
真的? 这把和那把比如何?
If you're gonna compare a Hanzo sword...
如果你要拿半藏的刀去比...
...you compare it to every other sword ever made -
那么其他所有的刀...
wasn't made - by Hattori Hanzo.
都不是服部半藏铸的.
Here you go. Wrap your lips around that.
给...大口喝吧.
So...
我说...
...which "R" are you filled with?
...你是什么感受?
What?
什么意思?
They say...
有人说...
...the number one killer...
老人的头号杀手就是退休.
People got a job to do, they tend to live a little bit longer so they can do it.
如果他们还有未竟的事, 就得活得久一点去完成.
I've always figured that...
我一直认为...
...warriors and their enemies...
...战士和敌人...
...share the same relationship.
...有着同样的关系.
So now that you're not gonna have to face your enemy no more
现在战场上你没有敌人可杀了,
...which "R" ya filled with?
...所以你是什么感受?
Relief...
轻松...
...or regret?
...还是婉惜?
- A little bit of both. - Horseshit.
- 都有点. - 放屁.
I'm sure you do feel a little bit of both.
我相信你两种感受都有.
But I know damn well that you feel one...
但我肯定其中一种比另以种多.
And the question was: Which one is it?
问题是...哪个多点?
Regret.
婉惜.
You know, you gotta hand it to the ol' girl.
你知道她早晚她会取代你的地位.
I never saw anybody buffalo Bill the way she buffaloed Bill.
我从没看过有谁 能像她那样使比尔着迷.
Bill thought she was so damn smart.
比尔认为她很聪明.
And I tried to tell him...
我试图告诉他...
...she was just smart for a blond.
...她只能算金发美女中比较聪明的.
Thanks a bunch.
多谢.
I'm sorry, Budd.
哦...对不起.巴德,
That was rude of me, wasn't it?
我太失礼了,对吧？
Budd, I'd like to introduce my friend, the black mamba.
巴德,我给你介绍 这是我的朋友...黑曼巴蛇.
Black mamba, this is Budd.
这是黑曼巴；这是巴德.
You know, before I picked that little fella up,
我选中这小东西之前,
I looked him up on the lnternet.
在网上查过它的资料.
Fascinating creature, the black mamba.
黑曼巴真是个神奇的动物.
Listen to this:
听好咯:
"ln Africa, the saying goes,
"在非洲,是这么说的...
"'ln the bush, an elephant can kill you, a leopard can kill you,
"在原野上,大象能要你的命, 豹能要你的命,
"'and a black mamba can kill you. But only with the mamba,
"黑曼巴蛇也能要你的命. 但是只有黑曼巴...
"and this has been true in Africa since the dawn of time, is death sure.'
"自开天辟地以来, 能确定让人致命.
Hence its handle, 'Death lncarnate."' Pretty cool, huh?
因此它被认为是死神的化身." 很酷吧?
"lts neurotoxic venom is one of nature's most effective poisons,
"它的神经性毒液是自然界中,
. "acting on the nervous system, causing paralysis.
"毒性是最强的一种, 能导致全身麻痹.
"The venom of a black mamba can kill a human being in four hours
"它毒液能使人在4小时内死亡,
"if, say, bitten on the ankle or the thumb.
"不过那是咬到脚踝或是拇指.
"However, a bite to the face or torso
"然而, 如果咬到脸或身体,
can bring death from paralysis within 20 minutes."
20分钟内就会从全身麻痹到死亡."
Now, you should listen to this, 'cause this concerns you.
现在听好咯,因为和你有关.
"The amount of venom that can be delivered from a single bite
"它咬一口所能释放出的毒液,
can be gargantuan."
非常巨量."
You know, I've always liked that word, "gargantuan."
我一直都挺喜欢这个词,"巨量"
I so rarely have an opportunity to use it in a sentence.
平时说话很少有机会用得到.
"lf not treated quickly with antivenom,
"如果不即时用血清治疗,
"ten to 1 5 milligrams can be fatal to human beings.
"10到15毫克就能致命.
"However, the black mamba can deliver
"然而黑曼巴一口...
as much as 1 00 to 400 milligrams of venom from a single bite."
就能放出100到400毫克的毒液."
Now...
现在...
...in these last agonizing minutes of life you have left,
...在你生命最后 几分钟的挣扎里,
Iet me answer that question you asked earlier more thoroughly.
让我好好回答 你刚才提出的问题.
Right at this moment...
此时此刻...
...the biggest "R" I feel is regret.
...我感受最深的是婉惜.
Regret that maybe the greatest warrior I have ever met
婉惜我所遇到 (或许是)最伟大的战士,
met her end at the hands of a bushwhackin', scrub,
怎么会死在像你 这样卑鄙无耻小人的手上.
That woman deserved better.
那女人应该死的更壮烈才对.
Bill...
比尔...
...I have some tragic news.
...我有个不幸的消息.
Your brother's dead.
你弟弟死了.
I am so sorry, baby.
真遗憾,宝贝.
She put a black mamba in his camper.
她在他住的活动屋里放了条黑曼巴.
I got her, sweetie. She's dead.
我把事情解决了,她也死了.
Let me put it this way:
这么说吧:
You ever start feeling sentimental, go to Barstow, California.
如果你觉得很伤心,就去加州巴斯多,
When you get here, walk into a florist and buy a bunch of flowers.
到了以后,去花店买一大束花,
Then you take those flowers to Huntington Cemetery
然后带着花去杭廷顿公墓,
on Fuller and Guadalupe, look for the headstone marked "Paula Schultz,"
再富乐和瓜达路培街交口, 找一块叫做宝・休兹的墓碑,
and lay them on the grave.
再把花放在墓上.
'Cause you will be standing at the final resting place of Beatrix Kiddo.
那儿就是你的小乖 (碧翠丝・基多)安息的地方.
- Marty Kitrosser? - Here.
- 玛缇・克超瑟? - 在.
- Melanie Harrhouse?
- 美洛妮・贺豪斯?
- Beatrix Kiddo? - Here.
- 碧翠丝・基多? - 在.
Look... I can be there in about four hours.
我可以四小时之内到,
Do you want me to come over?
你要我过去吗？
No, no, no, no. You need me, baby, I'm there.
不...不... 如果你要,宝贝,我立马过去.
OK. I'm leaving now.
好,我现在就出发.
You go smoke some pot or somethin', I'll be there soon.
你先抽口大麻烟或什么的, 我马上就到.
Gross.
恶心.
"T o my brother, Budd. The only man I ever loved. Bill."
"献给我的弟弟,巴德. 我唯一爱的人,比尔."
What's that?
那是什么?
Budd's Hanzo sword.
巴德的半藏刀.
He said he pawned it.
他说他拿去当了.
Guess that makes him a liar now, don't it?
那么他就是个骗子.
- Elle? - Bea.
- 艾儿? - 碧(翠丝).
Somethin' I've always been curious about.
有件事情我一直很好奇,
Just between us girls...
算是咱们女孩间的秘密吧...
...what did you say to Pai Mei to make him snatch out your eye?
...你对白眉说了什么, 他居然戳瞎了你一只眼睛？
I called him a miserable old fool.
我骂他可怜的老不死.
Ooh. Bad idea.
噢～馊主意.
Know what I did?
猜猜我干了啥？
I killed that miserable old fool.
我宰了那可怜的老不死.
How do you like the fish head, you miserable old fool?
鱼头味道如何呀,可怜的老不死？
I poisoned his fish heads.
我在鱼头里下了毒.
Elle, you treacherous dog.
艾儿,你这条没人性的狗.
I - give - you - my - word --
我一定会...
And I told him,
我告诉他,
"T o me, the word of an old fool like you
"对我来说, 你这老不死的话...
is worth less than nothing."
...一文不值."
That's right.
没错.
I killed your master.
我宰了你师父.
And now I'm gonna kill you, too.
我现在还要杀你,
With your own sword, no less.
就用你自己的刀.
Which, in the very immediate future, will become my sword.
再过一会儿,就成了我的刀了.
Bitch...
婊子...
...you don't have a future.
...你马上就玩完了.
Fucking bitch!
操你这婊子!
I'll kill you! You're fuckin' dead!
我宰了你! 你他妈的死定了!
You bitch! You bitch!
你这婊子! 你这婊子!
I'll fucking kill you, you bitch!
我要宰了你,婊子.
Oh, I'll get you!
我逮得到你!
I'm gonna...
我要...
Where are you? Lemme fuckin' at you!
你在哪儿? 让我操你!
I'm coming, you fucking bitch!
我来了, 你这臭婊子!
You're fucking dead! You're dead!
你死定了! 死定了!
Like most men who never knew their father,
就像很多从没见过 自己父亲的人一样,
Bill collected father figures.
比尔喜欢有长者风范的人.
The first was Esteban Vihaio.
第一个是 艾斯特邦・维黑欧.
Esteban was a pimp and a friend of Bill's mother.
艾斯特邦是个淫媒, 也是他母亲的朋友.
He ran a brothel in Acuna, Mexico for over 50 years.
他在墨西哥的阿库那 经营一家妓院超过50年了.
His army, the Acuna Boys,
他的保镳团叫"阿库那小子",
made up of the fatherless offspring of his whores, ran Acuna.
是那些妓女生的没爹的孩子, 他们负责娼寮的生意.
He ran the Acuna Boys.
而他是他们的头儿.
Now, at the age of 80, it would be this retired gentleman of leisure
他现在80岁了,就是这个 正在享受安逸的退休生活的人,
who could point me in Bill's direction.
可以告诉我比尔在哪里.
Senor Esteban Vihaio?
是艾斯特邦・维黑欧先生吗？
Yes.
正是.
May I join you?
我能叨扰一下吗？
Only on the condition that you call me Esteban.
如果你不连名带姓叫我, 只叫我艾斯特邦,那就可以.
- May I join you, Esteban? - Please.
- 艾斯特邦,我能叨扰一下吗? - 请.
Americana?
美国人?
Yes.
是的.
I speak a little Spanish, if you prefer.
如果你喜欢 我也会说一点西班牙语.
No, no, no, no. I prefer English.
不...不...,我喜欢说英语,
I haven't spoken it in a while,
我很久没说英语了.
but I would relish the opportunity to converse
尤其不能错过,能和像你这么漂亮 的小姐说话的机会.
It's my pleasure to be in the company of such a fine gentleman as yourself.
能和像你这样的绅士做伴, 才是我的荣幸.
I must warn you, young lady...
我得提醒你, 美丽的小姐...
...I am susceptible to flattery.
...我是很容易被赞美冲昏头的.
How may I be of service to you?
我能帮你什么?
Where's Bill?
比尔在哪儿?
Ahh.
啊...
You must be Beatrix.
那你一定是碧翠丝了.
I can see the attraction.
难怪他喜欢你.
I remember when Bill was only five years old, I took him to the movies.
我认识比尔时他才五岁, 我带他去看电影.
It was a movie starring Lana Turner.
是拉娜・图纳和约翰・嘉菲尔
The Postman Always Ring Twice, with John Garfields.
主演的"邮差总按两次铃".
And whenever she would appear on the screen,
每当她出现在银幕上时,
Bill would begin compulsively to suck his thumb to an obscene amount.
比尔就会情不自禁的吸允拇指.
And I knew from this very moment, this boy was a fool for blonds.
从那一刻起我就知道, 这孩子会傻呼呼的迷恋金发美女.
You know...
你知道...
...being a fool for a woman such as yourself...
...能像傻子一样 迷恋你这种金发美女...
...is always the right thing to do.
...也不是件坏事儿.
If we had met when I was back in business...
如果我在退休前结识你,
...you would have been my number one lady.
你一定会成为我的头牌.
- Well, I'm flattered. - You goddamn well better be.
- 过奖了. - 你一定会.
This... I heard you were driving a truck.
这是？... 我听说你开的是小卡车.
My Pussy Wagon died on me.
我的滦』醭祷盗.
The Pussy died. Hmm.
那滤懒耍
Bill shot you in the head, no?
比尔朝你头上开了一枪?
- Yes. - Hmm.
是.
I would have been much nicer.
如果是我,可不会那么狠,
I would have just cut your face.
了不起让你破个相.
You must forgive me.
对不起.
Please... you have a drink with me.
请...和我喝一杯吧.
Clara! (smooches)
克!
Coming.
来了.
Dos anejo.
(西语)
Gracias.
谢谢.
What were we talking about?
刚说到哪儿了？
Bill.
比尔.
- Where's Bill? - Where's Bill.
- 比尔在哪里? - 比尔在哪里.
Yeah. Hmm.
哦, 嗯.
Bill is at the Villa Quatro, on the road to Salina.
比尔在四季别墅, 去萨尼那的路上.
I will draw you a map.
我画个地图给你.
Bill is like a son to me.
比尔就像我的儿子.
- Do you know why I help you? - No.
- 你知道我为什么帮助你吗? - 不知道.
Because he would want me to.
因为这是他的意思.
Now, that I don't believe.
这我可不相信.
How else is he ever going to see you again?
不然他如何能再见到你?
Freeze, Mommy.
不许动，妈咪.
Bang, bang! Oh!
砰～砰～哦!
Oh! She got us, B.B.
她打中我们了，宝贝！
Mommy got us. Oh, I'm dying!
妈咪打中我们了！ 哦, 我要死了!
I'm dying.
我要死了.
Fall down, sweetheart. Mommy shot us.
快趴下，甜心. 妈咪击中我们了.
But little did Quickdraw Kiddo know that little B.B. was only playing possum,
但是，快枪手基多不知道的是, 小宝贝只不过是装死而已，
due to the fact that she was impervious to bullets.
因为她实际上刀枪不入.
I am pervious to bullets, Mommy.
我刀枪不入，妈咪.
Hey, get back down there. You're playing possum.
嘿！躺下！ 你在装死呢！
So, as the smirking killer advanced on what she thought
当冷笑的杀手的走向 她认为已经饮弹身亡的尸体时,
Bang, bang!
砰～砰～!
You're dead, Mommy. So die.
你死了，妈咪！ 快死呀！
Oh!
哦!
B.B.
宝贝.
Oh! B.B....
哦, 宝贝...
I should've known.
我早该料到...
You are... the best.
你是...最棒的.
Oh, Mommy. Don't die.
哦, 妈咪，不要死！
I was just playing.
我只是玩游戏而已!
I know.
我知道.
I told her that you were asleep...
我告诉她,你在睡觉.
...but that one day you'd wake up and come back to her.
但有一天你会醒来去找她.
And she asked me, "lf Mommy's been asleep since I was born,
她问我："如果我出生时 妈咪就在睡觉...
then how will she know what I look like?"
她如何知道我长什么样呢?"
To which I replied, "Because Mommy's been dreaming of you."
我回答说："因为妈咪一直梦见你啊!"
That's what I said.
我就是这么说的.
Did you dream of me? I dreamed of you.
你有没有梦到我? 我有梦到你哦.
Every single night, baby. Every single night.
每天晚上，宝贝！ 每天晚上！
I waited a long time for you to wake up, Mommy.
我等你醒来等了好久，妈咪.
Now, let me look at you.
现在让我看看你.
Oh.
哦.
My, my, my, what a pretty little girl you are.
哇～哇～哇～ 你真是个漂亮的小女生.
You're pretty too, Mommy.
你也很漂亮，妈咪.
Tell Mommy what you said when I showed you her picture.
告诉妈咪，我给你看她照片的时候， 你怎么说的？
- Come on, shy girl. - Mnh-mnh.
说啊,.. 别害羞.
Come on. You know what you said.
你一定记得的, 快说啊.
Come on. Tell Mommy. It'll make her feel good. Come on.
快呀！告诉妈咪！ 这会让她开心的！
- Mnh-mnh. - Yeah. Come on.
对呀, 快说.
I said... I said,
我说...我说,
"You're the most beautifulest woman I ever saw in the whole wide world."
"我说你是我见过这世界上 最美丽的女人."
That's the truth. That's what she said.
没错. 她是这么说的.
B.B., don't you think Mommy has the prettiest hair in the whole wide world?
宝贝,你是不是认为, 妈咪的头发是世界上最漂亮的?
- Yes, I do. - Matter of fact, it's better than pretty.
- 对啊. - 实际上,比漂亮更漂亮.
- What's better than pretty? - Mmm... Gorgeous.
- 比漂亮更漂亮, 该怎么说? - 嗯...美丽.
Very good. Gorgeous. Mommy is gorgeous.
好极了. 美丽. 妈咪很美丽.
Hmm. You know, sweetie, Mommy's kinda mad at Daddy.
你知道吗,甜心... 妈咪有点生爹地的气.
Why, Daddy? Were you being a bad daddy?
为什么？你是个坏爹地吗?
I'm afraid I was. I was a real bad daddy.
恐怕是的. 我以前是个很坏的爹地.
Our little girl learned about life and death the other day.
我们的小女儿 某天学到了生死的涵义.
Wanna tell Mommy about what happened to Emilio?
告诉妈咪埃米利欧的事吧.
I killed him.
我杀了它.
- Emilio was her goldfish. - Emilio was my goldfiss.
- 埃米利欧是她的金鱼. - 埃米利欧是我的金鱼.
She came running into my room, holding the fish in her hand and crying,
她跑到我的房间,手里拿着金鱼, 哭着说...
"Daddy. Daddy. Emilio's dead."
"爹地,爹地,埃米利欧死了."
And I said, "Really? That's so sad.
我说,"真的吗? 太令人伤心了.
How did he die?"
它是怎么死的?"
- And what did you say? - I stepped on him.
- 你说什么来着? - 我踩到它了.
Actually, young lady, the words you so strategically used were,
实际上,小宝贝 当时你很技巧的说...
"l accidentally stepped on him."
我"不小心"踩到它了.
To which I queried,
那我就问她...,
"And just how did your foot accidentally find its way into Emilio's fishbowl?"
"你的小脚怎么会 不小心踩到鱼缸里去了呢?"
And she said, "No, no, no. Emilio was on the carpet when I stepped on him."
她说,"不是...不是... 我是在地毯上踩到它的."
Mmm. The plot thickens.
嗯...像是剧情的铺陈.
"And just how did Emilio get on the carpet?"
埃米利欧到底是怎么 跑到地毯上的呢?
And Mommy, you would've been so proud of her.
妈咪,你会为她感到非常骄傲.
She didn't lie.
她没有说谎.
She said she took Emilio out of his bowl...
她说她把埃米利欧 从鱼缸拿出来...
...and put him on the carpet.
...放到地毯上的.
And what was Emilio doing on the carpet?
埃米利欧在地毯上干嘛呢?
Flapping.
一直跳.
- And then you stomped on him. - Uh-huh.
- 然后你就踩到它了? - 嗯.
And when you lifted up your foot...
你把脚移开时...
-...what was Emilio doing then? - Nothing.
- ...埃米利欧在做什么? - 什么也没做.
He stopped flapping, didn't he?
它不跳了,对吗?
She told me later...
后来她告诉我...
...that the second she lifted up her foot
...当她移开脚时...
and saw Emilio not flapping, she knew what she had done.
看见埃米利欧不跳了的时候, 她就明白自己做了什么.
Is that not the perfect visual image of life and death?
这不正是一幅生死交织 完美的画面吗？
A fish flapping on the carpet, and a fish not flapping on the carpet.
地毯上跳动的金鱼, 和地毯上不动的金鱼.
So powerful, even a four-year-old with no concept of life or death..
这么强烈的感, 即使一个对生死 完全没概念的4岁孩子都懂.
- You loved Emilio, didn't you? - Uh-huh.
- 你爱埃米利欧,是吗? - 嗯.
Well... I love Mommy, too.
那么...我也爱妈咪.
But I did to Mommy what you did to Emilio.
但我对妈咪做了一件 和你对埃米利欧做的同样的事情.
- You stomped on Mommy? - Worse.
- 你踩了妈咪? - 更糟糕.
I shot Mommy.
我开枪打了妈咪.
Not pretend shooting like we were just doing.
不是像我们刚才那样玩的.
I shot her for real.
我真的用枪打了她.
Why? Did you want to see what would happen?
为什么? 你是想知道会发生什么是吗？?
No, I knew what would happen to Mommy if I shot her.
不是. 我知道开枪打她 会有怎样的结果.
What I didn't know was, when I shot Mommy, what would happen to me.
但我不知道我打了妈咪以后, 自己会怎样？
- What happened? - I was very sad.
- 后来怎样? - 我很伤心.
And that's when I learned...
所以那时我学到了......
...some things, once you do, they can never be undone.
...有些事做了以后 就无法再改变了.
- What happened to Mommy? - Why don't you ask Mommy?
- 妈咪后来怎么样了? - 你怎么不问妈咪呢?
You OK, Mommy? Did it hurt?
妈咪,你没事吧? 疼不疼?
No, sweetie.
不疼,甜心.
Doesn't hurt anymore.
不再疼了.
Did it make you sick?
会使你生病吗?
No. It made me sleep.
不会. 我只是让我睡着了.
That's why I haven't been with you, B.B. I've been asleep.
所有没能陪你,我在睡觉.
But you're awake now, Mommy. Right?
但你现在醒了,对吧,妈咪?
I'm wide awake, pretty girl.
是啊,我全醒了,小美人.
B.B., would you like Mommy to watch a video with you before sleepy time?
宝贝,你要妈咪睡前 陪你看录相片吗?
Uh-huh.
嗯.
Mommy, do you wanna watch a video with me before sleepy time?
妈咪, 你愿意陪我 在睡前看录相片吗?
Oh, yeah! I would love to.
哦,当然,我愿意.
- Which one do you wanna watch? - Shogun Assassin.
- 你要看哪一片呢? - 幕府杀手.
No, B.B. Shogun Assassin is too long.
不好,宝贝,那片子太长了.
- Mnh-mnh. - No, it's not.
- 嗯. - 不长..
Well, then, I'll leave you ladies to it.
那好吧,小姐们,我失陪了.
(boy) When I was little, my father was famous.
我小时候,我爸爸很有名.
He was the greatest samurai in the empire.
他是全帝国家最好的武士.
And he was the shogun's decapitator.
他是幕府将军的刽子手,
He cut off the heads of 131 lords.
曾经砍掉131个诸侯的脑袋.
My father would come home to Mother and when he would see her,
当我爸爸回到家看见妈妈时 他就会忘记那些杀戮.
He wasn't scared of the shogun, but the shogun was scared of him.
他不怕将军,将军却怕他.
Maybe that was the problem.
也许那就是问题所在,
One night, the shogun sent...
一天晚上....将军派出了...
@ My man got a heart
# 我男人的心 #
@ Like the rock that's in the sea
# 像海里的石头 #
@ Well, no one told me about her
# 没人告诉我她的事 #
@ The way she lied
# 她是如何死的 #
@ How many people cried
# 多少人在哭泣 #
@ My man got a heart
# 我男人的心 #
@ Like the rock that's in the sea
# 像海里的石头 #
@ Well, no one told me about her
# 没人告诉我她的事 #
@ The way she lied
# 她是如何死的 #
@ How many people cried
# 多少人在哭泣 #
@ But it's too late to say you're sorry
# 即使难过也太晚了 #
@ How would I know?
# 我怎会知道 #
@ Why should I care?
# 我为何在乎 #
@ Please don't bother trying to find her
# 不必再去找寻她 #
@ She's not there
# 她不在那儿 #
I was just admiring your sword.
我正在欣赏你的刀.
Quite a piece of work.
真是把好刀.
Speaking of which, how is Hanzo-san?
说到这儿...半藏最近如何?
He's good.
他很好.
Has his sushi gotten any better?
他的寿司愈做愈好了吗？
You know, I couldn't believe it. You got him to make you a sword.
我简直难以相信, 他居然替你铸刀.
It was easy. I just dropped your name, Bill.
其实很简单, 我只是提到了你的名字,比尔.
That'd do it.
哈...那就够了.
@ Well, no one told me about her
# 没人告诉我她的事 #
I suppose the idea is we cross Hanzo swords. Am I right?
那么我们该用 半藏的刀来交手,对吧?
Well,
嗯,
it just so happens this hacienda has its own private beach.
正巧这个庄园有片私人海滩.
And that private beach just so happens to look particularly beautiful
海滩沐浴在月光下, 显得特别的非常美丽.
And there just so happens to be a full moon out tonight.
今天碰巧又是满月.
So, swordfighter, if you want a swordfight, that's where I suggest.
如果你愿意咱们就 去海滩用刀决斗.
But if you wanna be old school about it..
但是如果你想用传统的方式...
...and you know I'm all about old school...
...你知道我是最传统的,
...then we could wait until dawn and slice each other up at sunrise
...t那就等到天亮后, 再像正统武士道一般对决.
Iike a couple of real-life honest...
就像一对真的夫妻似的...
Now, if you don't settle down, I'm gonna have to put one in your kneecap.
现在...如果你不冷静一下, 我就在你膝盖上来一枪.
I'm just fuckin' with you.
哈哈哈～,我只是跟你闹着玩的.
Now...
现在...
...when it comes to you...
...至于你...
...and us...
...至于我们...
...I have a few unanswered questions.
...我有些不明白的地方.
So, before this tale of bloody revenge reaches its climax,
在这个血腥的复仇故事 达到最高潮之前...
I'm gonna ask you some questions, and I want you to tell me the truth.
我要问你几个问题, 你得照实回答我.
However, therein lies a dilemma.
然而...这也有矛盾.
Because when it comes to the subject of me,
因为一谈到到我, 我相信你不能也不会对我说实话.
Especially to me. And least of all, to yourself.
特别是对我. 甚至你不愿意对自己说实话.
And when it comes to the subject of me,
同时...只要一谈到我...
I am truly and utterly incapable of believing anything you say.
我不能也不会相信你所说的.
How do you suppose we solve this dilemma?
你认为该怎么解决这个矛盾?
Well,
哦...
it just so happens,
我突然想到,
I have a solution.
一个解决办法.
- Aah! - Gotcha!
- 啊! - 打中了!
Goddamn!
该死!
What the fuck did you just shoot me with?
妈的,你用什么射我?
My greatest invention. Or at least my favorite.
是我最伟大的发明, 起码是我最喜欢的.
Don't touch it, or I'll stick another one right in your cheek.
别碰它,不然我会在 你脸夹上再来一枪.
What lies within that dart, just begging to course its way through your veins...
你中的子弹里有一种物质, 现正开始在你血管里流窜.
...is an incredibly potent and quite infallible truth serum.
是一种非常强而有效的麻醉剂 它能让人说实话.
I call it "The Undisputed Truth."
我称它做"毋庸怀疑的事实".
Twice as strong as sodium pentothal, with no druggie aftereffects.
比有钠成分的麻醉剂还要强两倍.
Except for a slight wave of euphoria. You feel it?
除了会让你有点儿快感之外, 没有其他副作用. 感觉到了吗?
- Euphoria? - Yeah.
- 快感? - 对.
- No. - Too bad.
- 不. - 真糟糕.
As you know...
你知道...
...I'm quite keen on comic books.
...我很喜欢漫画.
Especially the ones about superheroes.
特别是那些关于超级大英雄的.
I find the whole mythology surrounding superheroes fascinating.
我对那些英雄式的神话非常着迷.
Take my favorite superhero, Superman.
拿我最喜欢的超人为例吧,
Not a great comic book. Not particularly well-drawn.
虽然不算好漫画,也画的不好...
Mmm.
嗯.
But the mythology...
但就神话上的意义来说,
The mythology is not only great, it's unique.
他不仅伟大,而且是独一无二的.
How long does this shit take to go into effect?
这捞什子的药性多久会发作？
About two minutes. Just long enough for me to finish my point.
大约两分钟吧. 正好够我讲完重点了.
Now, a staple of the superhero mythology is,
英雄式的神话中都有个特点, 他们同时是英雄也是凡人.
Batman is actually Bruce Wayne, Spider-Man is actually Peter Parker.
蝙蝠侠原来是布鲁斯・伟恩. 蜘蛛侠原来是彼得・派克.
When that character wakes up in the morning, he's Peter Parker.
当蜘蛛侠早上醒来,他是彼得・派克.
He has to put on a costume to become Spider-Man.
他得穿上蜘蛛服才会变成蜘蛛侠.
And it is in that characteristic Superman stands alone.
从这个观点来说,超人是更出众的.
Superman didn't become Superman.
他不是后来变成超人的,
Superman was born Superman.
而是天生的.
When Superman wakes up in the morning, he's Superman.
超人早上醒来,他就是个超人.
His alter ego is Clark Kent.
他的凡人面是克拉克・肯特.
His outfit with the big red "S" -
他衣服上的大红"S",
that's the blanket he was wrapped in as a baby when the Kents found him.
是当他父母 发现他时,原本就在包着他的毛毯上.
Those are his clothes.
那是他自己的衣服.
What Kent wears - the glasses, the business suit - that's the costume.
至于眼镜和西装, 只是他 为了要融入凡人社会中而穿的.
Clark Kent is how Superman views us.
克拉克・肯特只是 超人眼中我们的化身.
And what are the characteristics of Clark Kent?
至于克拉克・肯特的个性...
He's weak...
他软弱...
...he's unsure of himself...
...缺乏自信...
...he's a coward.
...他是个懦夫.
Clark Kent is Superman's critique on the whole human race.
克拉克・肯特是超人 对全人类的所下的定义.
Sorta like Beatrix Kiddo and Mrs. Tommy Plimpton.
有点儿像碧翠丝・基多和 汤米・普林顿的夫人.
Aso.
原来如此.
The point emerges.
总算你说出了重点.
You would've worn the costume of Arlene Plimpton.
你原本可以成维爱琳・普林顿的,
But you were born Beatrix Kiddo.
不过你生来就是碧翠丝・基多.
And every morning when you woke up, you'd still be Beatrix Kiddo.
你每天早上醒来, 还是碧翠丝基多.
Oh, you can... take the needle out.
你可以把针头拔出来了.
Are you calling me a superhero?
你叫我超级英雄?
I'm calling you a killer.
我叫你杀手...
A natural born killer.
天生的杀手.
You always have been, and you always will be.
你一直都是...以后永远都是.
Moving to El Paso...
搬去艾帕索...
...working in a used record store...
...二手唱片行打工...
...goin' to the movies with Tommy...
...和汤米一起去看电影...
...clipping coupons.
...收集折价券.
That's you...
那只不过是你...
...trying to disguise yourself as a worker bee.
...你想伪装成工蜂...
That's you tryin' to blend in with the hive.
躲在蜂巢里不被发现罢了.
But you're not a worker bee.
但你不是工蜂,
You're a renegade killer bee.
你是变节的杀人蜂.
And no matter how much beer you drank or barbecue you ate
不管你喝多少啤酒, 吃过多少烤肉,
or how fat your ass got,
或是你的屁股变得多肥,
nothing in the world would ever change that.
世上一切都不能改变这个事实.
First question:
第一个问题:
Did you really think your life in El Paso was gonna work?
你真的认为,从此能在艾帕索 过个普通人的生活吗?
No!
不!
But I would've had B.B.!
但宝贝本来是我的!
Don't get me wrong.
别误会我的意思.
I think you would have been a wonderful mother.
我认为你本来就会是个好母亲.
But you are a killer.
但你也是个杀手.
All those people you killed to get to me...
你能找到我之前所杀的那些人, 也都是高手,对吧?
...felt damn good, didn't they?
...感觉不错, 对吧?
Yes.
对.
Every single one of them?
每一个人都是吧?
That was the warmup round.
那是给你暖身的.
Now comes the $64,000 question.
现在到了要问你 值六万四千美元的问题了.
Why did you run away from me with my baby?
你为什么要离开我, 还怀着我的孩?
Do you remember the last assignment you sent me on?
你记得你给最后的一个任务吗?
Of course.
当然.
Lisa Wong.
王丽莎.
The morning I left, I was sick.
出发的那天早上,我病了.
On the plane, I threw up.
我在飞机上吐了.
So I started thinking:
我开始想:
Maybe I was pregnant.
我可能是怀孕了.
"Easy to use. Remove cap and urinate on the absorbent end for five seconds.
使用方便,打开盖子, 将尿液浸泡5分钟.
"Accurate results in only 90 seconds.
只要90秒,小窗口上 就会显示正确结果.
Fuck.
妈的.
What I didn't know...
我不知道的是...
...was that somewhere on my journey I had been spotted.
...旅途中我的踪迹已经败露.
With me in L.A., it didn't take Lisa Wong long to send an assassin of her own.
我到了洛杉矶不久 王丽莎就派出了杀手.
-  Hello, can I help you?
哈,有事儿吗?
Hello, I'm Karen Kim. I'm the hospitality manager of the hotel.
哈,我是金凯伦饭, 诚志饭店的客服经理.
I have a welcome gift from the management.
我们有个见面礼给您.
Oh, that's nice. Um...
真周到.
Can you just leave it by the door?
留在门下就好.
- You pretty good with that shotgun? - Not that I have to be at this range,
- 你很会使长枪吗? - 不是非得这么近我能才打中你,
but I'm a fuckin' surgeon with this shotgun.
我可是个使枪老手..
Well, guess what, bitch? I'm better than Annie Oakley.
告诉你吧,婊子,我比神枪手 奥克丽还准, 你在我射程内,
- And I got you right in my sight. - I could blow your fuckin' head off.
- 我的枪正瞄准着你. - 我能把你的猪脑袋轰掉.
Not before I put one right between your eyes, so let's talk.
不会比我打中你的眉心快, 咱们还是谈谈吧.
Karen...
凯伦...
...I just found out...
...我刚发现...
...right now...
...现在...
...not a moment before you blew a hole through the door...
...就在你刚破门而入后...
-...that I'm pregnant. - What is this?
- ...我怀孕了. - 说这干嘛?
On the floor by the door...
门边的地上...
...is a strip that says I'm pregnant.
...有个验孕器, 上面显示我怀孕了.
Bullshit.
鬼扯！
Any other time you'd be 100 percent right.
换做别时,你一定没错.
This time...
但这次...
...you're 100 percent wrong.
...你完全错了.
I'm the deadliest woman in the world.
我是世上能要人命的女人...
But right now...
但现在...
...I'm just scared shitless for my baby.
...有了孩子我却怕了.
Please.
求你!
Just look at the strip.
看一下验孕器.
Stay where you are and don't move.
待在原地别动.
I don't know what this fuckin' shit means.
妈的, 我不懂这表示啥?
The box with the directions - it's right there.
说明就在盒子上啊!
"Easy to use.
使用方便,
Remove the cap and urinate on the absorbent end."
打开盖子, 将尿液浸泡海绵处5分钟
Blue means pregnant.
蓝色代表怀孕.
I'll read it myself, thank you.
我自己会读,不用你多事.
Oh, OK.
哦, 好.
Say I were to believe you. What then?
好吧,如果我相信你, 下面该怎么做?
Just go home.
你回家吧.
I'll do the same.
我也回家.
Congratulations.
恭喜你!
Before that strip turned blue...
在验孕器变蓝色前...
...I was a woman, I was your woman.
...我是个女人, 我是你的女人
I was a killer who killed for you.
我是你的杀手...为你而杀.
Before that strip turned blue, I would've jumped a motorcycle
在验孕器变成蓝色前, 我愿意以从摩托车上...
onto a speeding train.
跳到高速飞驰的火车上.
For you.
为了你.
But once that strip turned blue...
一但验孕器变蓝色以后...
...I could no longer do any of those things.
...我再也无法做那些事了.
Not anymore.
再也不能了.
Because I was gonna be a mother.
因为我要做妈妈了.
Can you understand that?
你能了解吗?
Yes.
能.
But why didn't you...
但你为什么不...
...tell me then, instead of now?
...当时告诉我, 反而是现在?
Once you knew, you'd claim her.
你一旦知道,她就是你的了,
And I didn't want that.
我不希望那样.
Not your decision to make.
这不是你能决定的.
Yes.
我能.
But it's the right decision, and I made it for my daughter.
是我为我女儿所做的正确决定.
She deserved to be born with a clean slate.
她来到的世界应该是清白的.
But with you...
但是和你在一起,
...she would've been born into a world she shouldn't have.
...她就会生在一个她不该在的世界.
I had to choose.
我必须作选择.
I chose her.
我选择了她.
You know, five years ago,
你知道...如果5年前,
if I had to make a list of impossible things that could never happen,
要我列出绝不可能发生事情的清单,
you performing a coup de grace on me by bustin' a cap in my crown...
你在我的脑壳上来一枪...
...would've been right at the top of the list.
...绝对会排在第一位.
I'd have been wrong, wouldn't l?
但是我错了,不是吗?
I-I'm sorry.
对不起.
Was that a question?
那是个问我的问题吗?
Of impossible things that could never happen -
如果说你认为那是不可能发生的事， 这样说的话,你是错了.
Well?
那么?
When you never came back,
当你没回来...,
I naturally assumed Lisa Wong, or somebody else, had killed you.
我当然会想到王丽莎 或者其他什么人杀了你.
Oh! And for the record...
哦,说正格儿的...
...Ietting somebody think somebody they love is dead when they're not
...如果你没死, 却让爱你的人误会你死了,
is quite cruel.
是非常残酷的.
I mourned you for three months.
我为你伤心了三个月.
And in the third month of mourning you...
在我痛苦的第三个月,
...I tracked you down.
...我发现了你的踪迹.
I wasn't tryin' to track you down.
我不是故意要去追查你的行踪.
I was tryin' to track down the fucking assholes I thought killed you.
而是在追查 是找哪个混蛋杀了你.
So I find you...
结果我却找到你了.
...and what do I find?
...结果我发现什么?
Not only are you not dead...
你不仅没死...
...you're getting married to some fucking jerk.
...还要嫁给一个该死的混蛋.
And you're pregnant.
而且你还怀孕了.
I overreacted.
我...反应过度了些.
You overreacted? Is that your explanation?
反应过度? 这就是你的解释?
I didn't say I was gonna explain myself.
我没说我要解释什么!
I said I was gonna tell you the truth.
我只是要告诉你实话.
But if that's too cryptic, let's get literal.
如果我说的太复杂, 我就再说明白点.
I'm a killer.
我是个杀手.
I'm a murdering bastard. You know that.
我是个杀人的混蛋...你是知道的.
And there are consequences...
如果你伤了这个混蛋的心, 就会有很严重的后果.
You experienced some of them.
这你也曾经历过.
Was my reaction really that surprising?
我的反应真的 那么出乎你的预料吗?
Yes. It was.
是的...没错.
Could you do what you did?
你真能做出那种事吗...
Of course you could.
你当然能.
But I never thought you would, or could, do that to me.
可我没想到你居然忍心那样对我.
I'm really sorry, Kiddo...
我真的很抱歉,小乖,
...but you thought wrong.
...但是你想错了.
You and I have unfinished business.
你我之间还有未了结的账.
Baby... you ain't kiddin'.
宝贝...我知道你不是在开玩笑.
Pai Mei taught you the Five-Point-Palm Exploding-Heart Technique?
白眉真的教你五指穿心掌?
'Course he did.
当然.
Why didn't you tell me?
你为什么不告诉我?
I don't know.
不知道.
Because I'm...
因为我是...
...a bad person.
...是个坏人.
No.
不.
You're not a bad person.
你不是坏人.
You're a terrific person.
你是个了不起的人.
You're my favorite person.
是我最喜欢的人.
But every once in a while...
但偶尔...
...you can be a real cunt.
...你还真像个婊子.
How do I look?
我气色如何?
You look ready.
你像已经准备好了.
Well, well, well. If it ain't the little flower.
呵～呵～呵～ 像朵"小"花吧!
(narrator) Good evening, Mr. and Mrs. America and all the ships at sea.
美国人民大家晚安,一切就绪.
Let's go to press. Flash.
现在报导新闻. (闪光灯).
Do you have a magpie in your home?
你家里有喜鹊吗?
If you do, you are most fortunate.
如果有,那你是最幸运的了.
The magpie is the most charming bird in all the world.
喜鹊是全世界最迷人的鸟.
He is the best friend a farmer ever had.
也是农夫们最好的朋友.
Treat him gently. Treat him kindly.
对他要温柔,对他要仁慈.
And always remember, the magpie deserves your respect.
永远记住...喜鹊值得你尊敬.
Thank you.
谢谢你.
Oh, thank you.
哦, 谢谢你.
(magpie) Now, I'll tell you what I'm gonna do.
现在我要告诉你, 我要做什么.
I ain't got no headache.
我头不疼.
(magpie) Oh yes you have, brother.
老兄, 你当然头疼.
(@ male sings in Spanish)
(西语歌曲)
@ There's a nail in the door
# 门上有根钉子 #
@ And there's glass on the lawn
# 草地上有玻璃 #
@ Tacks on the floor, and the TV is on
# 门闩好 电视开着 #
@ And I always sleep with my guns
# 我总是带着枪睡觉 #
@ When you're gone
# 当你不在时 #
@ There's a blade by the bed
# 我床头有把刀 #
@ And a phone in my hand
# 电话在我手上 #
@ A dog on the floor
# 地上有只狗 #
@ And some cash on the nightstand
# 床头柜里有钱 #
@ When I'm all alone, the dreaming stops
# 当我独自一人时 就停止作梦 #
@ And I just can't stand
# 我实在无法忍受 #
@ What should I do? I'm just a little baby
# 我该怎么办 我不过是个孩子 #
@ What if the lights go out and maybe
# 如果电灯坏了 还有也许 #
@ And then the wind just starts to moan
# 然后风吹的呼呼叫 #
@ Outside the door, he followed me home
# 他跟踪我到家门口 #
Well, goodnight moon, I want the sun
# 月儿晚安, 我要太阳 #
@ If it's not here soon, I might be done
# 如果还不天亮 我可能就完了 #
@ No, it won't be too soon 'til I say goodnight moon
# 如果我不说月儿晚安 就不会很快天亮 #
@ Well, you're up so high, how can you save me?
# 但是月儿高挂 又怎么救得了我 #
@ When the dark comes here tonight
# 当今夜黑暗降临 #
@ To take me up to my front walk and into bed
# 带我过前厅到床边 #
@ Where it kisses my face and eats my head
# 在那儿亲吻我的脸 吃掉我的头 #
@ What should I do? I'm just a little baby
# 我该怎么办 我不过是个孩子 #
@ What if the lights go out and maybe
# 如果电灯坏了 还有也许 #
@ And then the wind just starts to moan
# 然后风吹的呼呼叫 #
@ Outside the door, he followed me home
# 他跟踪我到家门口 #
@ Now, goodnight moon, I want the sun
# 月儿晚安, 我要太阳 #
@ If it's not here soon, I might be done
# 如果还不天亮 我可能就完了 #
@ No, it won't be too soon 'til I say goodnight moon
# 如果我不说月儿晚安 就不会很快天亮 #
And, action!
开拍.
Cut.
停.
Oh, come on. Let's do it again.
哦, 别啦. 再来一次吧.